uh thank you for coming I'm sorry we're
starting late because of the traffic
accident um so we'll go L if you don't
mind uh
equally a little more maybe
um so I I thought first just uh I know
some of the people here I don't know
others and I thought uh tell you a
little bit about my background I know
Sean did some and thank you for that
um and then we'll and then we'll just
have a talk about something so I uh I
grew up in normal family in
Arizona and uh then
uh I don't know I was accepted to
Princeton and my mom was very proud and
uh she would go all to the neighbor
houses she went to the newspaper and got
an article p and and she was very proud
and and uh you know it was funny she'd
say uh how's your dog did you know my
son got a scholarship you know and then
uh she we loved each other very much I
have four brothers and uh no sisters and
my mom and then uh so I went there to
Princeton and it was very weird for me
cuz I'd never been anywhere in my life
and um it was difficult and then uh it
was all going really well I got uh
invited to the White House by the
president for a scholarship medal and my
mom went off to all the neighbors and
did that thing and uh made here got the
newspapers and we were happy we were all
happy and then um I got a phone call one
night and they said uh your mother died
you know
suddenly and uh it was really difficult
and we were really close and uh so I was
like almost
crazy I I remember I was hearing things
in the wind right I don't know if you
had your mom died but uh I was hearing
things in the wind and stuff like that
and then um I remember I I was running
to a class and I was a really good
student and I enjoyed school and I never
missed a class I was never late to a
class and I was running to class and
there was a tree in front of the my I
was in the religion department and I
took a Buddhism course although I didn't
know anything about Buddhism and I
wasn't interested in it much uh but
there was an Indian boy boy from India
was sitting in front of the tree he
looked like Buddha and uh he said come
here you know and I said no no I have to
go to class and he said this is more
important than class you know he made me
sit down and then he said you know if
you really care about what happened to
your mother you should go to India and
you know talk to the Buddhist people and
they can explain to you where happen and
then you will learn something important
that you cannot learn here you know and
he kept me for the whole hour of the
class and then by the end I was like
okay I'll go to India you know and it
was very funny because I I never been
anywhere you know and I went to the
school and I said can I go to India and
will you pay my scholarship money for my
trip and they said
sure I'm like oh no now I have to go and
uh and I went I got on the plane it was
Al alalia cheapest flight $400 and no
all these Grand Italian grandmothers in
the plane we had to stop in Rome and uh
I remember the plane took off from
Kennedy and it went straight up and then
it dropped straight down like for a
th000 ft and all these all the time
grandmothers are screaming like as loud
as you can scream and uh and that it was
such a weird trip and I didn't know
anybody and the boy said he would meet
me in the New Delhi Airport right so uh
I got to we landed in New Deli and they
opened the plane door and
uh I remember this intense incense smell
like this intense smell of India incense
you know hit hit me and then the rest of
the smells of India hit me and I was
like oh you know and uh in those days
India was a lot more dangerous and wild
and and I got out and it was all like
pigs and chickens and Childs and people
screaming and and I was looking for my
friend and uh he never
came uh to India he stayed home and so
I'm just standing there in the Delhi
airport and I don't know anybody and uh
I got I got a cab you know and I they
said where do you want to go I said I
don't know I need to stay someplace I
need a hotel and they're like you know
what they say in India my brother owns a
hotel you know which means his brother's
house right right and so I like go to
his brother's house and I I I remember I
went into the into the room and I I
locked the door and I was so frightened
I stayed there for 2 days I didn't come
out and uh finally he knocked on the
door and he's like are you all right and
I'm like no and he's like do you need
some food I said yes and then he he
brought me some food I remember it was a
real Indian meal like rice and
doll you know right and and he took the
time to explain each food to me and the
power of each food and he was very kind
and then he said you know why did you
come to India you know and I said well I
have to meet the Buddhist people I have
to ask them about my mother you know
what happened to my mom he's like
Buddhist people and he looks at his
watch he
says you're kind of late for the
Buddhist people I said why he said oh
they they finished in India a thousand
years
ago
then I'm like
well maybe I'll go home and I check my
ticket it's a 3 month ticket I have to
stay for 3 months and uh he said well
why don't you go to the Himalayas maybe
there are Tibetans coming out refugees
and they're Buddhists and you can talk
to them you know so so I ended up going
meeting them and I studied started
studying with them and then um I became
a monk and I entered a Tibetan
Monastery and I stayed for 25 5 years
and uh also in the United States at a
Mongolian Monastery which is Tibetan
they study Tibetan Buddhism so I spent
25 years like that the last uh 3 weeks
is a final Examination for they call g g
means like you know master of Buddhism
or something
so uh you debate in public you debate in
a Public Square in my Monastery there at
the time there 1300 months each one asks
you questions in public for 3 weeks in
tibetan and uh it's with the martial
arts they do it with martial arts and uh
they scream at you and then they dance
around and knock you and you know and uh
so this is what you study for 25 years
to to pass you know and then you have to
be really tough and and if you succeed
then you get a you seen those big yellow
hats that they put uh
yeah I like that and so I passed and uh
they gave me a big yellow hat and I
don't have any other degree I just have
this yellow hat you
know you know I remember I I told all my
friends I'm gu you and they're like
What's
that and then it was like that then
you're supposed to go back to your room
and they my my stepmother came for the
final ceremony and then they each monk
will give her a white scarf this is
Tibetan custom so she was she's pretty
short she's about 5T tall she was buried
under this mountain of white scarves and
you couldn't see her uh behind the
scarves and then um then they called me
on the telephone the abot so the
telephone at that time was uh we have
this seven-year-old
monks uh baby monks and you're not
allowed to take your vs till you're 20
one but you're allowed to live in the
monastery uh like if you're an orphan or
something like that so we have little
monks running around and they our
telephone and so you tell them you know
the Abbot told the little monk you you
go tell gishi Michael you know I need to
talk to him and then they run he says
run and they run and then but sometimes
they meet their Playmates and they start
eating candy and they forget the message
you know so they have you have to send
to or three baby marks and maybe one
will get through
you and so we didn't have any telephones
we didn't have anything and they so I
went to the Abbott and he was my teacher
and um I you know usually you only go to
the Abbot for discipline to be
disciplined they beat you that's why
Tibetan Monks are so
polite uh and uh so I I was nervous and
I said what yes you know yes master what
can I do and he said oh I wanted to
congratulate you you're the first
Westerner in our Monastery in 600 years
you know and congratulations he never
said anything good to me in my whole
life I was like stunned you know and
then he said but and I'm like yeah
what's the butt and and he said uh
you're a foreigner so you you we have a
special Examination for you we have a
second examination I'm like you didn't
say about anything second examination
you know then he said no no Foreigner
you have to prove yourself and uh I said
well what do I have to do and he said
you go to New
York you know and I said I hate New York
and he said you start a business I said
I hate business you know and it said
Diamond business I said that's the
dirtiest business you know they're all
Crooks and cheats and and then he said
you go to New York you start a diamond
business and then you use the principles
that we taught you
and see if you can make like a million
dollars in a year you know using Karma
using the principles of karma because
it's one thing to talk about it in a
monastery and it's another thing to do
it in real life and then by the way you
can
learn the challenges that real people
face making a living you know and so I I
said I didn't want to but they have
these fan
belts that they use on your bottom and
uh so he convinced me and uh and I went
to I went to New York and we started a
business and I I didn't really know how
to do what he wanted at the beginning
because it I I never they never taught
us how to use it in a business situation
they were it was always like meditation
or you know and I it was a struggle for
me to use those principles in a business
situation but we we worked hard I worked
hard and we started with three people
now we have 10,000 people uh it's $250
million a year and uh it was bought the
company was bought in 2009 by Warren
Buffett uh and I used the money for uh
charity and uh I'm often asked by people
to come and speak to people who want to
make money especially for Charities you
know so uh we've been for 25 years now
we've been been helping Tibetan refugees
we teach them to type on computers we
Supply them computers we build computer
centers for them and then they they type
in their ancient
scriptures and uh there there are we've
identified 200,000 books in the world in
libraries around the world and they're
typing through them there're about
10,000 books finished so they I figure
another 150 years so so we actually have
a plan and uh we're actually working on
an install free on the internet but it
took a lot of money to to do it it took
like5 $10 million and so I've been using
my money for that and I often meet
people who say you know teach me how to
do what you did cuz I have things that
I'd like to do with my life I have
projects that I would like to do and
they take money you need money to do big
projects and if you want to help help
seriously a culture or some endangered
literature or anything like that
cultural projects big ones they take
they take a lot of money and and so
people often ask me all over the world I
I travel the whole world and they asked
me to to give this talk about uh
especially how to make money for a
charity how to raise money for something
that you want to do uh that's going to
take a lot of
funding so I thought tonight uh I was I
was listening to the radio
NPR uh a couple days ago and they were
talking about the American middle class
and uh it was very interesting I mean it
didn't occur to me but I I think it's
true they said the American middle class
is
disappearing uh because the American
middle class used to the income of the
middle class was skilled manual labor
like uh automobile factories and this is
where you could get paid $30 or $40 an
hour and you would have enough money to
buy a home and uh you know they were
trying to Define middle class and it was
you have enough money to go out once in
a while and hire a babysitter for the
kids with your husband and you have
enough money to uh buy a home and uh you
know you have some retire you have money
left over for retirement and things like
this this was the definition of uh the
American middle class and now I have
friends even this week I have friends uh
they are educated they have college
degrees uh I met one of them last night
uh and I said you know you know I knew
he was looking for a job and I said well
what did you find and he said nothing
you know there's nothing for a college
educated person to do he said I I'm
teaching yoga he's a good yoga person
and he's teaching yoga but that that the
payment for yoga teaching is dropping I
mean in Tucson where where I do yoga
often it's the class is $4
so you know you can't make a living it's
difficult to make a living and it will
settle in the world it will settle
around $5 or $6 or something and then it
will be difficult and my other friend uh
he has a college degree and uh he's he
used to build restaurants and now he's
working at Starbucks and he was very
happy to get the job I think he started
yesterday uh he he worked for months to
get the job he really really worked hard
to get the job to get a $10 an hour job
so you you have a $10 an hour jobs a lot
of $10 an hour jobs and then you have
you know like investment bankers and
then in between there just a vacuum
there's nothing there you know the the
work has changed and uh and I travel a
lot we spend a lot of time in China I'm
in I was in Beijing last month we talked
we gave talks uh in the Forbidden City
near tenan Square to the MBA
students at Beijing University which is
their their main University in the
country and we spoke in Shanghai and and
uh Guang
Joo in South China so we talked we've
spoken along all throughout China and
I'm I'm looking
at at China and I'm thinking about the
United States and I'm thinking uh when I
was younger there were recessions I
don't remember the years when we started
the diamond company was in a recession
it was 1981 I think and there was a
recession going on and and and in
America when there was a recession you
always just kind of sted out you know
you you you you kind of didn't go out
much to restaurants and you you know you
you were careful to be nice to your boss
and uh you know but it was always
assumed that it would just change in 3
or 4 years you know that things would
would come back because every recession
America ever had had it just comes back
after a while I and and in my work uh in
the diamond company in the diamond
business it's International we I travel
all over one of my main jobs is to
evaluate other companies that want to do
business with us so I have to go to
their factories I sit in their factories
I watch the factory I'm on the assembly
lines I'm walking around the factories I
look at their books I look at how much
money they've borrowed you know things
like that and then we decide whether we
can collaborate with them or not and so
I'm used to evaluating an economy or you
know the strength of a of a of a country
or a company and
uh and I think in my opinion and I I'm
not a big Economist or anything I just
work a lot you know I've just been
everywhere and seen many many many
companies and worked with many companies
and I don't don't see any reason for the
recession to
stop indefinitely like I don't think
it's going to suddenly go back up I
think there's been a
dramatic and irreversible change in the
world market and uh because of the
internet uh largely but but now you are
competing with people all over the world
you know I do my Graphics design in
guadara I do my uh we do a lot of video
editing and and video creation we do all
that in uh guango South China and and
things like that the diamond cutting is
in uh India
Mumbai and then the uh the factories the
jewelry factories are in uh T outside of
Tel Aviv and uh what's that place up
North hia and then uh India Thailand
Hong Kong but and and what do you call
it Dominican Republic but nothing in
United States it's too expensive and and
it there's you can't find people who
really work that hard
and and uh
so so I'm concerned you know I'm worried
about my country you know frankly I I
see a pattern my friends are all it used
to be when you had worn out clothes you
took them to Goodwill and now you sell
them you know or you had junk in your
house and and you just gave it to
Goodwill you you were happy cuz they
would come and take it away but now you
have a garage sale cuz you need 30 bucks
or you need 60 bucks and that's that's
good money now you know that means
something and things have changed things
have changed radically and I think
there's a lot of
uncertainty about the future more than
before you know uh it's much worse now
in America like you can't know what's
going to happen here and uh and I I'm in
China a lot and I I was very what do you
call
it Chinese are like Arabs you know like
the Press has convinced us that Chinese
are evil and Arabs are evil like the way
the Nazis used to be evil and I forget
who it was before that probably the
Indians or something you know but the
Press chooses someone who's evil and
then they I saw a video it was on the
news of a child in China hit by a car
and uh the guy didn't stop I don't think
he saw the child ever you know but it
was played over and over and it was said
to be proof that Chinese don't love
their children or something and and it
was just this kind of uh propaganda that
the Americans get on somebody like
Palestinians or something and they go
crazy you know and so anyway I was I was
nervous when I went to China you know
and uh I'm a monk I wear robes I hid my
robes in my suitcase you know I wear a
suit the whole time and and uh and then
uh nothing happened just I met nice
people you know and then I went back a
second time and I was more comfortable
and and I made some friends and then I
went back a third time and a fourth time
and a fifth time now I feel like very
comfortable with everyone and I realized
they have one head and two arms and two
legs and they also love their kids and
they just want to be happy and they're
no different from but somebody from
Sacramento people in be being are are
absolutely no different from people from
Sacramento and they're not mean or cruel
and they don't want to take if they want
to take over the world they could and
they're not interested you know and so
it's
like then now I feel like I'm just at
home you know I'm just there and I'm
working with them and same with Russia
the first time I went to Russia I I told
them I feel very nervous here you are
enemy you know they asked me how do you
feel we had a project for 14 years in St
Petersburg to catalog the Tibetan books
we paid for that I paid for that and uh
so I used to go and and one night
they're driving me around and they said
well okay how do you like Mother Russia
you know and I said you guys are all
right you know you're just like
Americans you're it's cool I like you
and they I said but you know it's funny
when I was a kid they told us that you
were the enemy and and I said even my
first grade teacher used to tell us to
hide under the desk in case the Russians
tried to bum us you know like and I
always wondered how hiding under a desk
would help uh during a nuclear war you
know and uh and then they started
laughing all the Russian guys started
laughing and I said well you know it's
not that funny and uh and they said no
no you don't understand our teacher said
the same thing about you you know they
told us the same thing about you that
you wanted to kill us and bumb us and we
had to hide under our desk also and and
we were laughing and that's the way the
world is once you travel a lot and you
see a lot of countries everyone's the
same everybody wants the same stuff and
the world is suffering this the world is
has the same suffering people all over
the world are trying to make a living
people all over the world have families
people have kids they also want to make
some money they also want to have a
refrigerator and and have things for
their family and they're not evil Arabs
Chinese
Germans am they're all the same we're
all the same we just want to have things
to live you know and we're all the same
and then we all have the same worries
okay so what I've done tonight I thought
for
tonight uh there's a
famous uh text that we studied in the
monastery toet it comes from India
it's and uh he said there are six
problems s that everybody in the world
faces in in your life trying to make a
living uh trying to support your
children uh you know trying to live
through a recession or or maybe see the
recession
change by the way I'm hopeful I believe
that uh we could establish a new kind of
economy uh a new kind of global economy
the idea of local economies is over it's
finished you know we I do book contracts
all the time and somebody in uh somebody
in Spain was telling me can I have the
rights to uh to the Spanish translation
of your books and I said no and he said
well then I'm not going to sell them and
I said well I don't care I mean somebody
in Mexico will translate it and people
will order it online I can't tell you
they're not going to mail it across the
border I it's over those those days are
over you can't have the rights to a
country because Amazon will ship
anywhere and it doesn't mean anything
anymore so I think we will settle into a
nice beautiful global economy I believe
it will be prosperous I believe that
poverty areas will finish and that there
will be a a high standard of living for
globally for the whole world it can no
longer be some people are rich and some
people are poor it can't be like that
anymore if you can if Amazon will ship
anywhere those days are gone you know uh
a a little guy in Africa can send can
sell yoga mats to zuda yoga you know
from Zimbabwe and they'll ship them we
we print our books in India and they
just ship them from New Delhi and it
doesn't matter you can't stop it you
know it's going to be like that uh so
can we set up an economy that that's
good for everybody and maybe it's better
in the long run it'll be a little a
little bit shaky for the wealthy
people cuz now people in China are also
wealthy and they also need oil and
they're willing to pay more than an
American so for us it's a little
frightening but I think we got to get
used to it and everything will settle
fine everybody will have enough we just
have to get used to the process okay so
tonight I thought to talk about the
process in the end it will be fine we
will be prosperous people in Mexico
people in China people in India Africa
we'll all be prosperous it's okay uh but
we have to get used to that it's weird
to be in Beijing and know that they have
more money than my city you know they're
more prosperous than Phoenix Arizona it
took it was a little bit of a what do
you call hurt my ego you they're like
I'm like asking them for can you loow me
some you know you know and it was like
new for me cuz as an American you're
used to like studying around the world
and thinking you're number one and I
think it's going to be a global economy
and people will be pretty much
equal uh but in between here and there
there'll
be there will be and there will remain
six
fundamental problems of anyone who works
for a living okay which is everybody
eventually so those those were outlined
1800 years ago and I I wrote it out for
you so let's go through them okay I
propose we go through them
so I'm going to start on on the first
page past the cover okay after the
cover in it
says these are the six challenges that
any person who's trying to make a living
who's trying to support them El you will
always find these six challenges they
will face you wherever you go whatever
country you live in it doesn't matter
everybody has them okay number one we
can't be sure what will happen with our
job you don't know what's going to
happen next week okay you work for a
company does anybody not have a reading
raise your hand and Mercedes will give
you one there's a gentleman
there two
people anybody else not have one there's
a lady right
there good anyone else no okay can't be
sure what will happen with your job like
it doesn't matter where you work it
doesn't matter what your position is you
can own the company you can be the
president of the company I was the vice
president of my company 19 years okay
and uh you can lose your job in in 5
minutes okay and you know that people
who've worked in a company big company
it's just the way it is okay anybody can
lose their job in 5 minutes there's no
certainty and that causes a lot of
stress for everybody okay in a in a
company any kind of job that you have
you could lose it in 5 minutes if you
have your own company you could have a
car accident you could lose your ability
to work you don't know okay we are all
in that position all of us in this room
we share the same doubt about our life
and it wears you down it wears on you it
doesn't matter if you're Tom Cruz or you
know he also doesn't know if he'll get
another movie jump he doesn't really
know anything can happen to anybody
people die suddenly it happens all the
time time and and you don't know you can
get fired you can lose everything in a
moment in 5 minutes okay usually it's
unexpected and you know I used to be in
the board meetings where we decided
those things they'd say we have to cut
500 people and you choose you choose
you're like no no you choose you you
know it's very brutal it's very to be on
the firing end is also brutal you can't
sleep at night uh the person that you
fire hates you
forever and if you don't fire them the
company fails and everybody goes home so
it's like that uh anybody we don't have
certainty about what's going to happen
to us that's that's our condition Human
Condition number
two you meet people they want to get the
job I'm thinking of the guy who got the
Starbucks job his initials are RH okay
some of us know him uh he's so happy
this week that he got the job job he's
been uh schmoozing the manager of the
Starbucks for like 6 months and uh they
finally got the job and he's all excited
and you know and I know that in 6 months
he's going to be complaining that he
hates Starbucks and it's so boring and
they don't pay him and he can't take
time off and you know that's the nature
of things we get the job that the dream
job we get the thing we wanted the most
it it applies Partners also and then 6
months later you're like dissatisfied
already you you don't like it anymore
okay that's just human nature There's
Something About Us number one we don't
know the future we have we're all not
sure what's going to happen next week if
we'll be alive we don't know next week
and then number two anytime you
something does go well then after a
while you become dissatisfied and you
want more or you want something
different okay this is human this is
this is who we are the point of
tonight's talk is can you change these
things is it possible to change these
things okay that's that's why I'm here
okay number
three you always lose your good gigs you
know your good jobs okay uh you finally
settle into a job you know any job you
ever get you will
lose okay any job you ever get you will
lose that's just life those of you who
are old enough have been to it a few
times you know it doesn't matter how
good the job is it doesn't matter how
good the company is it doesn't matter if
their product fact
machines is desired by the whole world
you know it can change and then suddenly
nobody wants that thing at all you know
and then suddenly the company's gone and
then you're gone every position you ever
manage to scrape together you will
lose that's that's our condition that's
Human Condition it doesn't
nobody's all jobs will end all companies
will end all lives will end all cities
will end in in rubble it's just the way
it is okay can you change
it that's why we're here okay uh number
four you have to start over again and
again so I don't know especially
relationships you know you you're with
somebody for a couple years or 10 years
or 20 years and then suddenly it's over
you know and you're like you like walk
back into the kitchen you know and
they're gone the moving truck drives
away and you're like God damn now I have
to start over you know I have to do the
whole thing over again you know I
thought I had it all figured out you
know the third marriage you should have
it figured out you know and uh and now
there's this desolate desolate feeling
you know you you're just standing by
yourself in the kitchen and half the
pots are gone you know they took all the
good ones and the ones with tops right
and uh and you're standing there you're
like damn I have to start the whole
thing over again I even have to go buy
pots you know and I have to buy some
dishes and you have to start over again
and this is a human condition okay at
work especially I think it's seven times
you will be retrained in your life if
you live that long uh you will have to
learn a new job completely new job so it
doesn't matter what you've trained your
yourself in or what you did in college
or what you're qualified
at uh those of you who are old enough
you know that's that you will be asked
to do something different and then you
have to learn it and you have to learn
something totally different and that
that will happen five six seven times in
your life with relationships also you
have to start over again and it's very
frustrating it's like I spent 10 Years
Learning you know
stenography and now they got
iPhones
I did I I I learned stenography and then
yeah yeah I was desperate for a job I
came out of the monastery I couldn't do
anything you know that's before I
started D okay anyway
uh number five every job we ever get
goes up and down every day okay even if
you hang on to your job even if you stay
at a job there's a constant anxiety
while you're at work there's a constant
anxiety you never have a purely good day
you know like it gets like 4:45 and you
said the whole day's been good you know
I think I'm going to have my first
purely good day you know and then the
boss calls you and says you know we got
an order you have to stay till 9:00 and
then you're like there goes my one good
day perfect day you know and it's like
that it's always like
that The Human Condition is that your
job the time you spend in your office
just go up and down constantly all these
huge swings and then your mood swings
with it right oh I'm the best yoga
teacher in the studio and then suddenly
you're not anymore and then you know and
then it goes up and down and this is
It's like a roller coaster your whole
life and the stress the anxiety never
ends of this up and down relationships
also you know oh I finally got it down
me and my husband are finally tight you
know and then he's like by the way honey
I want to tell you about somebody then
you're like and then there's this thing
again then it it swings again you know
and and life is this total up and down
it's just oscillation constant waves
right it never stops you never get arest
you can't go to your husband and say
don't say anything stupid today the
whole
day you know just let me have one day
things don't change you know it doesn't
work uh I think number six is the
saddest which is in the end we are alone
okay uh you you come to your your job
usually you apply as an individual right
and you get fired as an individual
usually and you lose your job and you're
alone I I've done it you've done it you
walk down the street yeah away from the
building that was your home for 10 years
or 15 years and you walk down the street
and that's it and you're alone there's
nobody with you okay in the end uh you
can have a big family you can have a
husband wife you can have children uh
you can have a company that you've
worked with for your whole life but
they'll come the day in my company they
gave you the silver
pin it was a gold pin with a diamond in
it you know and they would they would
call me the the the HR would call me and
they say we need a 10-point diamond
cheap i' say they're going to fire
somebody they're going to fire somebody
old you know somebody's been with the
company 20 years it's going to get their
pin and they want to cheap diamond to
put in the pin you know like I this
particular size of diamond is kind of
unusual and I I saw they're going to
fire somebody you know and then that
person it's so uh what do you call
it uh it's so sad to see them leave
everyone else is staying in the office
and they're cleaning out their death and
then they there's this kind of last look
that they give which is kind of mixed
bitterness and anger and and uh sadness
and uh uncertainty and stress and they
got to go home and tell their family
right and there's this look on their
face and then you don't want to see it
you go to the bathroom or something you
know or you get the security to take
them out cuz you don't want to take them
out you know and uh and then they go and
they walk down the street and you see
them walk down the sidewalk and they're
alone and in the end we're always alone
okay you die
alone uh you will leave every situation
you've ever entered you will leave it
alone okay we that's our condition so
these are six very sad things about
human life they relate a lot to our
economy our our work
nowadays but they also relate to your
personal life your
relationships and the question is is
there any way to change that okay can
these conditions be changed and and I
mean
human what do you call it common wisdom
they common wisdom Common Sense
CW common wisdom huh conventional wisdom
is that you can't change these things
these
are at a certain age in your life you
assume they cannot be changed and you
just learn to deal with it okay yeah I
know I'm alone in the meantime I'd like
to have a partner and I'd like to have
some children I but I know that in the
end I'm alone and uh I know I have to
lose my job someday but can I enjoy it
as much I mean what little enjoyment I
get out of my work let me have it don't
hassle me you know I know I know all
that stuff is true but I I choose to
ignore it because if I thought about it
every day I'd be miserable you know so
we get to a kind of they call it
maturity you get to a kind of maturity
they call stability I don't sit in bed
all day depressed I still get up and
fight you know every morning I put my
leg out and I still get my shoes on and
go to work even though it's all crazy
and and it's all going to end you know I
still do it and
uh and and what's happened to to us as a
herd is that we're used to it we we
decided to live with it those of us who
didn't my brother committed suicide you
know and and he decided no more you know
but the rest of us we we decided to
stick it out you know and for better for
worse we're going to stick it out and we
assume we can't do anything about these
six things my goal tonight is to try to
present a way that you could change
those six things okay all six and that's
my goal tonight I I want you to go home
with at least one crazy person thinks
you could change these you know no I
mean and then you you won't believe it
all tonight and but you'll go home and
you'll start to doubt whether they could
be changed or not and that's all I want
to do uh in tibetan they
call doubt your first doubts about
something that you should have believed
all along your first suspicion that
there could be a different way okay and
that's all I want I don't want to uh
sell
you my ideas I just want you to suspect
that they might be right by the end of
the night I want you to be
suspicious that maybe these six things
are not inevitable okay that's my
proposal okay that's going to take some
doing uh we'll go for like another 20
minutes and then I'll uh we'll take a
break I think there's Refreshments
aren't there I never talk anywhere
unless they have Refreshments yeah okay
good so I don't have to leave
um and
uh I'll go I I I'm going to start I had
a nice meeting today at lunch I had a
lunch meeting with some people
I'm sorry if you were there you get to
hear this thing again but maybe it's
okay uh there's a very simple powerful
traditional way to explain the ideas
that could change those six conditions
okay there there's a very simple ancient
way of explaining that and and I was
thinking I had like three alternate ways
ready and then I thought oh forget it
you know uh let's just do this same
thing okay so here we go uh in the
Ancient Asia the teacher asks a question
and you answer immediately or you get
hit and so the first row has to be
attentive
uh it it's
amazingly it works very
effectively uh you know students missing
and they obey the teachers and anyway
it's not a lot in the United States
uh what so just answer when I ask a
question just just answer from the from
your don't think about it just answer
I'm not trying to trick you okay uh I'm
trying to stop those six problems okay
what is this
thing yeah it's a pen uh if a dog small
puppy dog came in here walked down the
aisle you know and and I waved this
thing in front of the puppy dog and I
and I wave it in their face what will
they do they will bite it okay I'll play
with it
okay does the dog see this as a pen no
you can say no what do they
see yeah the same thing which I see as a
pen you know how long it took to find
that on
Google the same thing which I see as a
pen uh they see as something to cheour
okay now question who's right the dog or
the human you can say both I it's a very
honest natural answer yeah the dog can
enjoy Che I also enjoy chewing art uh
the dog can validly enjoy chewing on it
the human can use it to write no problem
both are right okay next question more
difficult if I put this object
here and all the people leave the room
for their
Refreshments it's not just water right
you're
not she's like not committing
there good uh all the humans leave the
room all the dogs leave the room at that
time which one is it a pen or a
chor
indeterminate yeah indeterminate who
said that beautiful answer that's the
first time anyone ever said that exact
answer and I think it's the most correct
indeterminate is good it could be either
one depending on who walks in the room
who walks back in if a human walks back
in it becomes a a pen if a dog walks
back in it becomes a Choy what if they
walk in
together both it becomes both good no
problem at that moment there are two
realities running in the room no problem
parallel dog reality human reality okay
no problem even on that object two
realities I'm running there's a true toy
reality and a pen reality no
problem next question
therefore you can answer my next
question
easily if I see this as a pen is the pen
coming from the pen or is the pen coming
from me your perception yeah it must be
coming from me okay I mean the dog
proves it okay and and you
know it sounds stupid and simple but
just think 250 million okay I I'm not a
big uh business person I don't like
business business it's not interesting
for me I use the money for good things
but I but I did make a 250 million
company I I made help make it and and I
use these principles so they sound
simple and they sound kind of childish
but they're not okay you can save
Tibetan culture you could save Tibetan
Minature with this idea so so don't
think I'm just being dumb okay it it
sounds dumb but it's not so dumb okay so
we can say that the pen is coming from
me then why do I perceive it as a pen
and why does the dog perceive it as a
Choy we say there's a seed in the dog's
mind there's
a I don't know a good word vas how will
you translate it
Jay seed
energy there's like a tendy huh tendency
yeah there's a seed for tendency or
something like that it's a difficult
word let's say seed okay let's just
leave it there's a seed in the dog's
mind to see it as a CH toy and there's a
seed in my mind to see it as a pen
okay how do you plant that seed you see
if I could control the planting of those
seeds if I could understand how the
seeds are planted in my mind to see the
things around me I could control my
future I could design my reality you see
I could be like Neo in The Matrix you
know like he figured out everything with
a computer program right and and if I
could learn if there were a method of
planting seeds in my mind which caused
me to see everybody in my world and
everything in my world then in theory I
could design next
year okay I could design a better
partner or I could upgrade my current
partner uh like let's say they don't
like to wash dishes or they don't have a
good job or they're lazy or everything's
coming from me the pen is coming from me
my partner's good qualities are coming
from me and my partner's failings are
coming from me also
so in theory if I became a master of
planting these seeds in my mind I could
control what I see next month I could be
a stupid untrained Monk and make $250
million company that waren buffet b okay
you I could do it if I knew how to plant
the seeds you see so tonight I just want
to talk about that principle how do you
plant seeds Okay in the mine because
what's true for the pen is true for
everything in your life your job your
partner your family your
city your body it's all coming from
seeds in your mind so if you if I could
help you to plant certain seeds to learn
a system of planting seeds then in
theory you could have the things you
want okay I I always say there are like
five things that people want I've been
teaching for I don't
know uh
uh almost 40 years okay and uh in my
life experience there's five five or six
things people want number one they want
to be financially independent everybody
would like to have enough money to do
whatever they want you know I don't know
anybody who wouldn't like that you know
I it'd be nice to have as much money as
you want you see something you know you
want it and you just buy it and you
don't have to ask anybody do I have
enough money you just buy it I'm not
talking I think most of us are not what
do you call it ostentatious we don't
want to
be have a five karat diamond ring or
three cars or I think especially people
in the United States and and even
California I would dare to
say uh no I think people in California
are a little more advanced in this
regard to other people in the country
and to other people in the world you are
wise enough to know that three cars is
more trouble than one you know and I'm
not kidding no I'm not it's not a joke
you you evolved and there are countries
where people don't believe that they
don't understand that in Beijing there's
what is there 500,000 new cars there
last year you know it's like weird it's
like scary cuz everybody wants two cars
or three cars and then I think Americans
have reached a point because they've had
Prosperity so long I think most
Americans on understand that if you have
a house with 17 rooms in it it's just a
lot of cleaning you know and it'd be
better to have a small efficient
Pleasant house I have a small efficient
Pleasant house in a m on a mountain but
you know in front of me there's nothing
and and that's fine I don't need I don't
want more than that cuz I I have trouble
cleaning the two rooms you know and I
don't want to clean four rooms so I
think we've reached that kind of
evolution in America because we've
always had enough people in other
countries haven't had that yet and they
they get there they all get there so but
wouldn't it be nice to have enough money
to do anything you want and not to
stress and especially I'll tell you
something interesting like I go around
the world giving these success talks to
thousands of people it's not unusual for
a thousand people to come to a talk in
China or Mexico or you know and then
actually number of people want to make a
lot of money they want to
be prosperous wealthy and I say why I
get them we go on these three-day
Retreats three-day success
Retreats I make them leave their home
they have to come out to the countryside
with me in every country in Bulgaria in
Russia in Argentina in China in Malaysia
we go out of the city we go to a
resort I I keep them for 3 days they
have to do yoga they have to do
meditation H and they have to join
discussion groups and they have to tell
me what they want and then for 3 days I
get to work on them you know and then
they go home and they try to get it you
know so a lot of people say money the
first thing I want is money and then I
say why and you'll be happy to know I
think Jay was talking about it today but
you'll be happy to know I would say 90%
of the people who want more money want
it because they want to serve the world
they want money to help other people and
it's very it makes me very happy I'm I'm
happy to report to an audience in
Sacramento California that all over the
world people want money because they
want to do something good for others you
know and that's cool I'm happy so it's
not bad to have money in that sense it's
useful it's it's precious it's a nice
thing everybody would like to have
Financial Independence number two
everybody would like to have a nice
partner or family right most not
everybody wants a family most people
would like to have a partner it's one of
life's greatest pleasures and I don't
care if you're still angry about your
last breakup but uh but in the end
you're going to want another partner
okay after it wears off you're going to
want another partner it's it's like one
of the greatest joys in life to have a
good partner you know like a really nice
loyal sensitive financially independent
uh
who works you know uh
polite nice person to live with cuz it's
lonely to come home you can have a lot
of money and then come home
and and there's nobody there to share
your day with that's that's lonely it's
not
fun we all we've all had trouble with
Partners but in theory is it possible to
have a good one you see what I mean one
that is good for a long
time uh we would like that everybody
would like that I think most people
would like that in my experience in the
world most people would would like to
have a nice partner uh that's a second
thing you can have money you can have a
partner but if you don't have health if
you have a bad back or you have some
chronic health problem or or you don't
have energy if you lost your energy lost
your youth the the energy of Youth a lot
of people spend their youth to get money
they spend their life juice the battery
to get money and when they get the money
they're too old to enjoy it you know
there's nothing sadder than a old
rickety guy in a
stingray you
know you know and you know there should
be a law that the old guys have to give
to somebody who can appreciate it uh you
know who can use it uh who's 20 you know
can attract some girls with the car and
uh so I think those are three things
that people want they
want they want to be
financially secure and then they want uh
companionship and then we want uh good
health and energy we'd like to be strong
and and healthy you know and then you
get to the mental you know things we'd
like to be peaceful in our mind no no
depression no nervousness no anxiety
uh we would the emotions jealousy anger
desire we would like to somehow be free
of those
chains of of being jealous all the time
of people or or judging other people all
the time or getting angry easily or
upset easily we would like to be free of
those
mental poisons they're called poisons
into bit so I think that's like a fourth
goal and then obviously
uh I was I went to a city in in China
called changu it's not it's on the this
side of to and
um it's famous for moku anybody know
moku you're you're cheating you've been
to
China Madu is a kind of
tofu that was invented in Chango and
they use Irma Irma is a red uh
peppercorn and uh it tastes like a good
Mexican
chili but different it has a unique
taste once you eaten mapu you can't eat
anything else so I there's a restaurant
where they invented mafu and chenu so I
like I got to find this restaurant I
worked like two days and I found this
old wooden restaurant where they
invented mapu you know and I walk in and
there's all these waiters like in
China in a restaurant there'll be 25
waiters and two people eating and uh you
know so I sit down by myself and I'm I'm
experiencing mafu you know oh man this
is it this is the original mafu you know
I got to learn how to cook this you know
and then everyone else is just watching
me you know and I'm I'm thinking why
don't they buy some mafu you know and
then I realized they don't have any
money they don't have the money you know
I'm alone in the restaurant eating the
mapu and with all these people watching
me and and it wasn't fun anymore it was
totally not fun and I left I left the
restaurant cuz I couldn't do it anymore
I couldn't stuff myself on my favorite
mafu in front of 20 people who didn't
have the money to buy it and it was just
really uncomfortable so I think the last
thing we all want like Bill Gates Warren
Buffett once you get that much money
what do you
do you start helping other people it's
just not fun to be the only person
eating in the restaurant you know like
if you get
successful and you have all the money
you want and you have a beautiful
partner and you have good health uh if
your health gets constantly better and
better your energy is more and more then
you feel guilty when you see other
people and they don't have these things
and then you can't enjoy them because
the other people don't have them so then
you get this desire it's a human it's a
beautiful human trait that everyone of
us if we became wealthy we would start
to give it away because we we would want
other people to have it also so I think
these are basic five emotions I'm happy
to report to you in Sacramento
California that everybody in the whole
world that I've met wants to help the
whole world they they don't there's no
culture however evil the newspapers say
they are uh who would feel comfortable
to eat in a restaurant if nobody else
could eat every person in the world
would be uncomfortable uh with that so I
I think those are we want to help the
world in the end deeper than the desire
for sex deeper than the desire for food
is the desire to serve other people to
be the mother for other people it's a
human it's a deep-seated human desire
and it's Universal everybody in the
world has it you know it's beautiful
it's cool and we all have it it's a
beautiful thing okay so these are the
five goals of a human being so how can
we use
seeds uh to achieve them
okay I'm going to skip the paper okay
that often happens I'm
sorry it's not
important we'll get
there
sorry the people who printed it at the
last minute they're always
like
uh let's just go straight to those five
things okay do you mind somehow I think
we'll solve the other things by the way
uh
[Music]
and people ask me you know why why are
you a monk you're a buddist monk why are
you going around teaching people to get
rich uh it's CU I don't I don't like to
eat in the restaurant by
myself okay understand it's a kind of
compassion I thing it's not an evil
thing you know uh we all know that three
cars is not useful and that 17 rooms is
is just more cleaning right um
uh but you also have anxiety about your
credit cards and the debts you have and
your car paying off your car loans and
school
loans uh things like that you have those
anxieties why not get rid of them why
why have why make people go through that
if they don't have to you see if if you
can stop it why not stop it that's one
kind of human pain right so okay first
one uh we went through it today in the
at lunch I'm sorry to repeat myself you
guys can fall asleep now I'll wake you
up when we get to something new uh there
are four steps to achieving uh any of
those goals that we talked about to
repeat financially independent any money
I can do anything I want uh secondly I
have a beautiful partner third I have
what health health energy useful energy
Health good health
fourth my mind is peaceful my mind is at
peace and then finally I'm doing
something to help the whole world I I
can bring those things to other people
okay so let's go through them one by one
and we'll forget the reading I think by
the end the reading will solve
itself
um where did it
go yeah
okay uh how do I put put a seed in my
mind to see those five things okay how
do I place the seeds in my mind to see
those five things because the pen is if
the pen is coming from me this is a
common technique in in tibetan debating
you learn it you you lull the audience
with a small example a pen and they
happily agree that the pen is coming
from me everybody agreed right nobody
disagreed then if if I take you to a
place where you accept that the pen is
coming from you then you must accept
that everything else around you is
coming from you you don't have a choice
I tricked you I you thought I was just
talking about a pen I'm talking about
your husband I'm talking about your kids
I'm talking about your job your city the
the sky the roads the traffic the
accidents on the roads they're all
coming from you okay you can put seeds
in your mind for anything how do you put
it there there are four steps okay and
that you should write down somewhere
okay you have a paper right just use it
write it down you can you can throw it
on the street when you get outside
um number one decide what you want okay
I suggest you focus on one thing okay
don't try to do all five things at once
okay like whatever sounded best to you
write it down now okay I want I want to
have as much money as I want to do
anything I want including help all the
people I'd like to help or I'd like to
have a peaceful state of mind you know
I I don't want to have anxiety in my
mind or depression or doubts or anger or
okay you decide you write down what you
want
okay I'll give you one minute
more if you're the thing you wrote down
was I don't know what I want we we can
also fix
that that's also coming from seeds and
you can change it it's very cool okay
there's nothing you can't change with
seeds okay got it okay number
two you have any money do you have some
money this is how I supplement my
income
uh it's like usually it's much more
effective with A1 dog bro
uh so I'm going to show you how to plant
a seat so I want let's say for example I
want money and again I'm not saying
you're greedy and you want a zillion
dollars and you want you know a big
mansion or something like that cuz we I
I agree we all are mature enough to know
that's not going to make you happy it's
just more work okay but I would like to
have a
nice three two two room house on a
mountain with you know debt free you
know it's mine you know it's got solar I
have a rainwater catchment I don't need
anything if there's a nuclear war I'll
be fine so
uh so how to make money how do you plant
a seed in your mind so watch
uh planting a seed
requires that you find someone else who
needs the same thing okay step number
two is to find someone else who wants
about the same thing okay I had somebody
ask me this Burning question I think it
was in
Detroit if I want a vanilla ice cream
can I give chocolate ice
cream yes okay it just has to be close
Okay ice cream any kind of ice cream all
right so I want to be
financially independent I I don't want
to have to think what I want in my life
I don't know about you but I don't I
want to reach a place where I don't have
to think about money and then I can
think about the other things I want to
think about so I I don't want to be rich
but I want to reach a place in my life
where I don't have to think about my
bills some and it I'm there I don't pay
my bills somebody else pays my bills you
know they just they're right here in
this room but I won't embarrass them and
I don't pay the bills I don't see the
bills they just get paid that's nice
okay if you want to get
there uh you have to do it for somebody
else you have to try to do it for
somebody else okay you if you want
to be financially
independent you have to take a pet
project of helping someone else to
become financially independent okay you
need another person to plant a seat it's
like soil you cannot plant a seed
without another person not possible if
you don't want to do that you can leave
now
okay if you you have to do it for
somebody else that's the rule and
there's no exceptions you cannot plant a
seed without another person it's not
possible there's no such thing you can
just leave now if you want to if you
don't want to help somebody else just
leave now cuz it it won't work and I and
I claim that you'll never be happy and
you'll never get what you want okay you
need somebody else okay so anybody else
so let's say Bonnie is uh step number
two I choose Bonnie okay you you don't
just going to just relax uh I choose
bunny okay and uh I'm going to help her
become financially independent I'm not
saying you have to give money away
wildly
randomly it doesn't work either okay you
don't have to give money people always
come to me should I give money to the
homeless I say if you're sure they're
not using it for drugs and alcohol maybe
but that's not the point you see you
choose
anybody who who needs to make some money
and you help them just help them okay so
I'm not suggesting you go hand out
dollar bills to everybody or $10 bills
it was a dollar bill right just kidding
uh here's how you plan to seed for money
okay and I'm very serious I'm not joking
and I did it so I'm speaking the reason
I tell you my life story is that you
believe me you know I did it and I'm
there and it's nice and I don't think
about my bills much so anyway uh I want
to put SE in my mind for money I choose
step number two I choose a person who
who who needs some extra money and I
help them make it you don't have to give
it to them just help them give them
advice okay who's the last person in the
world who can advise other people about
making
money a person who doesn't have enough
money who wants to use this system a
person who doesn't have enough
money uh
but when it comes down to is intention
okay not skill okay if you really want
to help someone else that plans a SE
that's enough just want to help others
is enough and then do your best whether
you succeed or not is is frankly not so
much up to you as it is up to their
seats okay don't get frustrated do your
best I I got to help her make money but
I don't know how just help just try that
plant a SE so okay here then watch watch
my hand I give I put the money in her
hand then I Let Go who's witnessing the
action you she is and you are I am my
mind records everything in my life I did
Sean mentioned I did a three-year
Meditation Retreat in a in a room 3
years okay and uh I can tell you
everything you ever saw in your life is
still in there every TV advertisement
you ever heard is still in there they
were singing to me like after 12 14
months these spaghetti advertisements
you know uhoh spaghetti uhoh you know if
you're my age you know uh sheer I don't
know what is but you're in deep
meditation in in the 16th month and all
you can hear all day is
spaghetti and uh everything you do is
stored in your mind okay trust me I I I
can I I I thought okay so I I hand it to
her I let go I am witnessing my own hand
letting go that plants a seat okay that
plants a seat so step number two find
someone who needs something similar to
what you
want okay and then you know trust me
people come to me all the time I don't
know anybody who wants what I want and I
say check for 24 hours get back to me
you know and then they come back 24
hours later they come back I found 10
people who want what I
want you were ignoring them your whole
life you know of course there's people
around you who want those five things
duh but you just ignored them up to now
now you need them right you need someone
to plan a seene with now suddenly they
appear in your life you know oh she also
wants some money you know they were
there all along you didn't care you
didn't notice them in this EX you learn
to notice other people's needs which is
also nice so when I let go I see this
planted in my mind okay so step number
two make a
plan choose somebody okay choose
somebody make a
plan I often tell people uh make a plan
to take them out to like Starbucks or
something okay you're going to take them
out to a certain Starbucks and you're
going to sit down and you're going to
say I know you're buried on
credit card debts or I know you still
have your student loans 80 it's usually
80,000 I don't know why I guess that's
what it costs but all my friends have
$80,000 school loans 30 years later you
know and you're like okay I know you
have the same problem that I had and uh
I want to help you okay just like that
just say Let's help each other let's go
out and have coffee and I will I'll give
you some suggestions uh make them your
pet project okay if you don't feel like
doing that you this this is not going to
work for you and I claim that nothing
else will work for you and you will you
will go through those six things your
whole life you will go up and down you
will lose jobs you will get new jobs you
will make money you will lose
money Partners houses families and it'll
keep going over and over again sooner or
later in your life you have to help
other people that's the only way sooner
or later you'll figure it out might well
do it now it saves time right so you
have to find somebody else who needs
what you need and then step three
guess step two is to choose them step
three is to do it okay just do it take
them out somewhere and help them okay I
I often do it at a coffee shop you just
sit down and talk and say I don't have
all the answers for your life but I'm
going to help you I'm I'm committed to
meeting you once every two weeks and
that's enough okay and that that that
will bring you Financial Independence
okay it's very interesting if you plan
to see but okay here's a but this is
like those TV shows that end uh at
halfway through at the end of the night
and you have to come back
tomorrow
uh you know many people who are generous
who didn't make 250 m
n okay you know that I don't have to
tell you the reason you don't jump up
and kiss me right now is that
uh in the back of your mind you hesitate
because you say I know people who are
generous and they're still poor you know
I know people who are very generous I've
seen people give money over and over to
other people my mom and she was always
struggling for money her whole life you
know she never got through that you know
so I I respect your
sentiments but I don't think it will
work because I've seen the opposite and
then my answer is step four okay you
have to know step four all right step
four is
uh is a
process which nurtures the seed in your
mind during the time that the seed stays
in your mind it has to be nurtured it
has to have fertilized ER water sunlight
there are mental and moral equivalents
of fertilizer sunlight water and you
have to apply them to your mental seeds
or they don't
grow okay and they'll sit there forever
by the way you can't destroy them they
will sit there forever and they will
never open okay it's like a watermelon
seed that you leave in a drawer okay is
the seed good yes does the seed work yes
will it make a water
yes but you have to plant it and you
have to water it or it just will never
do anything so I I'm I'm I'm
claiming that almost all of you already
have enough seeds in your mind to get
anything you want you already did many
kind things to other
people all of us have we all do bad
things and we all do good things and you
already have countless seasoning your
mind from having served other people
kind things you've done for everyone
here has done beautiful things for other
people those seeds are sitting there
like watermelon seeds in a drawer and
you have to water them and then you
probably don't have to do much new stuff
just water them and they will open okay
and then you can have money or you can
have a partner or what you want you can
have so cleverly I'm going to tell you
step four after
refreshment um uh so that you don't make
do you have announcements you want me to
make Mar me well they're still paying
attention you want to come up and
no let do beginning of the next month
okay we'll do that beginning next um I'd
like to introduce some of the staff that
I travel with I usually travel with
about 15 staff we're on our way to uh
Latin America we leave tomorrow morning
at
5:30 uh and we we do tours we do tours
of many countries so some of the staff
are with me uh tonight some of I'd like
to introduce them because if you have a
question about your own life uh you
could ask you could ask them okay I I
call it like shopping uh at the
supermarket I'm going to ask them to
stand up one by one and you check them
out and if it looks like they might have
the answer for your question or if you
feel a karmic connection with them then
during the Refreshments I encourage you
to talk to them okay so don't be shy you
paid to come I think I don't remember
but but you're here and and they're
trained some of them have been trained
for 20 years and they're good at it uh
so ask them questions if you see someone
that strikes your fancy then uh just go
up to them and ask them a question I'm
going to ask them to stay up here during
the break okay so I think
uh let's see uh Mark Ross can you come
up the first four people live in
Sacramento so if you if you if you want
to have a free advisor for the rest of
your
life Mark am deer can you come his wife
partner uh Brandy Davis where are you
are you here yeah David
Fishman are you
okay yeah so those those four people
live in Sacramento and then travel with
me uh oh Sean Fister lives in San
Francisco uh so they're
local uh some of my my usual staff are
uh Mercedes B the singer she handles
mostly Russia and China she does
about 10 cities in Russia and China but
she'll still talk to you
um Bonnie suie just got married she's
cool she just she she was one of the
first employeers of Apple Corporation
and uh she did not buy the stock which
is why she still has to work and um and
then polycom Corporation so she's does a
lot of our
financials uh J Ellie V do you
mind come she's the bill person okay she
does my she's the financial person and
uh let's see Nicole can you come
up uh Nicole's a a yoga teacher she can
help you
if you're into that Rebecca are she's
not too
mobile you going to do it
anyway okay did I leave anybody
out I don't think so okay so there's
your choices okay people you can talk to
during if you have a question during the
break uh don't be shy okay engage them
ask them because many many many people
during the break they got the answer
they were looking for in their life so
you have specific needs in your life
that you know I may not talk about so
use the use the braid okay use that time
just come don't be shy okay they've only
bitten a few
people okay we'll check
Ann also um we're very interested in
coming back to the area and doing some
more um corporate programs uh with The
Diamond Cutter Institute um if you are
interested in helping with those events
in the future um or you have any ideas
of a company or corporation that might
like to
bring and it's only in the last year or
so that it occurred to me that it's
possible that the easiest thing is the
most powerful thing or the the most
happy thing to do is the most powerful
thing and it just seems I grew up in
America a judeo Christian background and
we kind of felt that you have have to be
crucified to do your part you know and
no and it's just part of our culture you
have to suffer to be successful or
something like that and uh but if you
think carefully you know if you're
really
open-minded is it
possible that the most Pleasant thing
you could do would be the most powerful
thing see you know so that happens to be
the case so step number four I I have
come to call it coffee meditation
because my llama when he taught it to me
uh he called it coffee meditation
so I'll tell you the whole story cuz we
have a little bit I'm going to go to
9:30 is that okay or a little
bit
uh I'm not going to get any sleep anyway
uh you might as well suffer with me he
he used to sit and watch he was a
Tibetan llama very cranky old school
very high llama and then uh I some Demon
gave him a television
and and then he got addicted to New York
Yankees baseball and uh he would watch
New York Yankees baseball and then I
would come home from the diamond company
I had to come home to the monastery
every night and then uh so some of my
time I lived in a in a Mongolian
Monastery in New
Jersey and uh he was be
upstairs and uh only the Abbot is
allowed to watch television and I W I
wasn't allowed to watch television so I
didn't have a television and but then I
would hear him upstairs and I'd hear the
baseball game you know and I'd be like
how could I get up there you know and
uh so teton's like uh tetan tea which is
made with h butter and salt and Nutmeg
and soda powder water and it they taught
me to make it and they got me addicted
to it and at the time I was drinking
like 20 30 cups a day and uh it keeps
your mind very sharp and you know
R and uh he would sit and watch baseball
s said oh I'll make him some tea so you
have to pour all those things in and
then you have a plunger uh like a butter
churn and you have to plunge it and then
uh then you pour it into a cup and you
have to run upstairs and you knock on
the
door and they in tiet they the Llama
says sh sh means what you it's the word
you use for dog it means come like come
in and he say sh and then I'd come in
you know and he'd be sitting with his he
always had his rosary and his team never
lost after he started praying for
them if you like baseball and you he he
was a m fan mainly actually and that was
the year they won the World
Series after losing uh 17 years in a row
and uh and he cheated he was I swear he
cheated all these weird things happened
if you know baseball it was a historical
Year anyway he was doing all this and uh
so he would ignore me and I'd say oh R I
have tea you're supposed to say you know
in bed you're supposed to
go which means I respect you and so you
have to get down on your knees and and
you you got to say and then you you
can't look at the llama and you have to
offer the tea and then he would take the
tea and then I would sort of go like
this and get behind him and and watch
the baseball
game and
uh and then he would be like totally
absorbed the game and then uh but he had
eyes in the back of his head also and he
then he'd say you're still here his
voice was like that he's like you're
still here I say yes R you know he'd say
why are you still here and I'm like oh
real I had I worked for how many
hours it was 12 or 13 hours you know I I
just I'm just fried L you know I I need
need a break I just want to watch TV you
know just let me sit here I won't bother
you just let me watch you know he'd
say that was his answer to anything I
said then he he didn't hit me so I
figured it was
okay and then he's like then after a
while he's like did you meditate today
and I'd be
like no you know I was on the bus at
5:30 to New York you
know I then I was on the subway and then
I had to walk to work from the subway
station and we our our building's in
Tribeca so
anyway then I I come back you know and I
I was so he said have to meditate you
got to do your meditation so I'd say
okay and I get up to leave you know and
one day he said uh you can sit on the
couch and meditate so he had this big uh
teak teak wood couch framed with gold
cloth with gold threads to it real gold
and some wealthy guy gave him this cou
you know and he didn't let anybody sit
on the couch the DI Lama came to visit
one day and he sat on the couch but no
one else is allowed to sit on the couch
if you get close to the couch he hits
you with his M with his with his Rosary
he whips you with his rosary you know
and so I'm like you sit on the couch you
meditate now he talked just like Dirty
Harry then uh and he loved dirty hairing
I think there was something going on and
uh you sit on the couch you know and
then sometimes a llama will ask you to
do something wrong because they want to
hit you you see so they're they're
checking to see if you will sit on the
Forbidden couch you know and when you
sit down they start hitting your in the
rosary you know and I'm like that's okay
R I'll sit on the floor here you know
I'm happy on the floor sit on the
couch and I'm like God there's a rule in
Tibet if a mama has to ask you three
times they hit you so you might as well
sit after the second
time you might as well sit on the couch
cuz they're going to hit you anyway so
but there's a chance they won't hit you
if you sit on the couch so anyway I sat
on that couch you know and then he's
like lie down on the
couch and then into bed your feet are
considered uh very dirty they're
considered very profane your feet are
profane you're not allowed to put your
feet on anything it's like put your feet
up on the couch you know I'm like he
really wants to hit me you know he he's
drawing it out you know and
I'm like okay okay I sat on the couch I
lean back and then prop your head up on
your hand like this you know and look at
the ceiling and I'm like I thought you
wanted me to meditate that's meditation
then he swing
his he twirl his Rosary which is like a
threat you know and he like do that and
I'm like that okay what do I I do now in
pain he's like it's like this and he's
like it's like that pose they made us do
today I was cheating okay I had my hip
on the ground anyway uh so he's sitting
like this and he said okay we're going
to do coffee meditation I'm like what's
coffee meditation go go make yourself
some coffee come back you know I run
down make coffee come out drink the
coffee I'm drinking sit the coffee okay
look at the ceiling okay think about the
good stuff you did today did you do any
good stuff today for anybody I'm like
yeah he says you remember the the church
do you remember the church I'm like he
went to a church one day he went to a
cathedral uh the pope issued a what do
you call he did incca I forget the bu
told everybody they had to do something
and it and it was that every Catholic
church had to invite people from other
religions to give lectures at the church
so they called us and they said you have
a Buddhist llama there yeah can he come
and give a talkar cuz the pope said we
have to and he's like okay I'll go you
know and we I remember we were walking
down the middle of this beautiful
cathedral and um he's looking everywhere
he's like Mike Mike he called me Mike
Mike get your pen out like what he says
make a list
you says you need Windows like this in
the temple you know these colored
windows they're great you know you can
put Buddha and Tara stained glass
windows you know and he's he's really
excited about the church you know and
he's like we got to do all this stuff
he's we're walking down the middle with
the priest you know then he looks over
to the side and there's a a little uh
room right on the side of the church and
a priest comes in the back door and this
good-looking lady goes in the front door
of this little room and he's
like he's like tell the priest you know
you know what are they doing there you
know and and the priest is like oh don't
worry uh it's all okay and he said what
are they why are they going in there and
he said don't worry there it's a
confession he says oh that's good we do
that too you know and he he said what
did they do in there well there's a
window and then she tells him her bad
stuff that she did and then and then
then what happens then the priest tells
her to do prayers on a rosary like 100
prays on a rosary oh that's like
montrous good
idea you know that's really good you get
with all your bad karma that's a great
then he
says where's the other one and and the
priest is like what do you mean he's
like you know where's the room on the
other side and he says no no we just
have the one he says what you got to
have a room on the other side well we
have one is enough for the church you
know he no no you don't understand the
priest comes in the back the lady comes
in the front she tells the priest all
the good good stuff she
did and then the priest is like that's a
good
idea and uh so there's a tradition in in
uh ancient
India that you have to give equal time
to reviewing your
mistakes and equal time to reviewing the
good things you did today so coffee
meditation is
uh and they're very strict about it it's
when you lay your head down on the
pillow uh if I let the head go to the
pillow I fall asleep but that's the way
it is I fell asleep today in that stupid
pose I forget what it
was did you notice I like dead out
anyway
uh you put your head like this and you
look at the ceiling I I prefer this okay
you can try the pillow but it's a little
dangerous and you go like this and you
look at the
ceiling that's meditation okay when you
were in high school and your thinking
about your boyfriend and you're
like you know that's
Focus okay the no it means the sense
organs are turned off seriously you're
like and you're not looking to your eyes
your eyes are open but you're not seeing
anything right it's called
Tibet so uh you you get into this space
on your bed and and the and a normal
normal person's mind will go to one of
three places and and you check it out
you try tonight okay on your pillow as
you start to go to sleep check it out
the human mind goes to one of three
places number one your ex partner from
10 years ago it's something they said 10
years ago okay I had that very beautiful
female uh llama uh Western what's her
name it was in uh Oregon or something to
ton children yeah I I went to a talk by
her she gave a really good talk and then
she said your boyfriend forgot that
thing he said to you the same
afternoon but 10 years later you're
still thinking about it you know like he
he did he did a number on you you know
he said something to you 10 years ago
your ex and you're still thinking about
it 10 years later and he forgot it like
half an hour after he said it you know
like he should have to think about it
right and and uh that's one thing we
think about people who hurt us in the
past and then we think about worries
about the future right we wonder will I
have my job next week will my husband
leave me you know you don't you worry
about things and then uh me I make plans
I make Grand plans you know like I I use
up today by planning tomorrow and I'm
never in today you know and uh those are
the three things that your mind will go
through to when you're on your pillow
and you then you have to wrestle with
your mind okay like you have to
like you know now your mind is worrying
about next week or your mind is still
thinking about your ex partner 12 years
later and then you have to grab onto
your mind like a wrestler like an
Olympic wrestler you know and you flip
them you know I say we're not going to
think about that stuff he's like what
are we supposed to to think about and
say we're going to think about all the
good things we did today the person we
took to Starbucks for step
three we did a good job didn't we it's
not Pride it's appreciating who you are
okay it's not
Pride it's it's appreciation so okay I
I'm trying a new method of making money
it doesn't involve slavery to some
company or to the state of California I
guess that's popular in this town
uh you
know
uh you today I tried a new way to make
money rather than just working blindly
my whole life and getting my measly
little pension you
know I took someone to Starbucks and I
talked to them about ways that I could
think of that they could make more money
and that's my strategy for paying off my
credit
cards okay got it I'm going to plant
seeds by helping someone who else has
Financial
stress and that's my new system you know
it's the Crazy Diamond color thing that
guy you know I'm going to try it for a
couple weeks if it works okay if it
doesn't the worst thing that happened is
you took someone to Starbucks you know
so think about it on your pillow I today
I did something possibly revolutionary
you know I tried a new way of making a
living which is that I helped someone
else to get the thing that I wanted and
in theory that's going to plant a
seed and in
theory that's going to
create an object called money that's my
pen okay
uh okay because it's coming money comes
from you also money is also coming from
you okay okay
so I'm doing an experiment with my life
to make money I'm going to help someone
else I'm just going to sit with them at
Starbucks and give them suggestions
about how to pay off their credit cards
and stuff like that okay and I I'll see
how it works okay and then at night the
guy said I had to do step four or it
wouldn't work okay he
claimed that I could make $100
million if I just lay my head on my hand
correctly you know and uh think today I
I tried a new way to make money which is
helping someone else to make money okay
and I understand it's a little weird but
I'm willing to give it a
try okay if you're a big shot in a
corporation in New York you get three
weication you know it's a point of pride
in a big Corporation in New York you
know you come out of the owner's room
you know and you're like walking down
the hallway and and you kind of turn to
someone and you say I got 3 weeks
vacation you know and they're all just
common slaves and they only have two
weeks vacation you know you're like I
got I'm a VP and I got three weeks
vacation you know and then you feel
really happy you know you gave 49 weeks
you get three you know and from the
outside you know from a truly what do
you call it objective Viewpoint you're
insane you know you're trading 49 weeks
of your life for free and one of those
weeks you're going to wash your clothes
anyway it's no it's the whole deal the
whole system is a scam you know why not
give me 26 weeks and I'll work 26 weeks
you know make it 50/50 we have a rule in
our company we work 183 days days a year
that's the rule we cannot schedule a a
talk or any business meetings or
nothing 183 days off per year and 182
days on you know and that's our Rule and
that we don't break it for anything she
arranged a flight back from China to get
to the airport by 11:30 p.m. because we
didn't have another day we would have
gone over 180 to you see I'm serious it
was a big struggle and we did
it so I'm going to try something new you
know I I'm going to make money by
helping someone else to make money just
as an experiment I'll try it what the
heck if I can get a an extra two weeks
vacation it's a it's worth it I'll give
it a shot you know give it a
shot this system
requires that on the bed at night
as you fall off to sleep you think about
the things you've done to help other
people and there's no expiration
day okay it can be 5 years ago it can be
10 years ago it can be 15 years ago
anything you did to help another
person if you're if you just feeded some
water it will grow the seed will grow
cuz the seed cannot be destroyed all
mental seeds are
are indestructible they cannot be
destroyed they will stay in your mind
for decades any kindness you've ever
done is sitting there like a watermelon
seed in a drawer and if if you put some
water on it it will grow okay and then
you can have what you want you already
have those things okay okay that's
number four is it
difficult it is difficult cuz your
mind's going to your mind will go off to
some ex partner or some future plan or
some anxiety you have about the future
and you will have to wrestle and fight
and struggle physically with your mind
your mind will slide it'll keep Sliding
Away to your problems or or someone you
don't like okay and then you have to
grab it by its neck you know
Scruff and get the heck back here you
know we're thinking about the good
things we did today no no we have
financial
problems shut up shut up no no my boss
said something unkind to me shut up get
back here you know that effort the
effort of struggling with the mind it's
that is the true meaning of meditation
okay I meditated in the monastery for 25
30 years okay that's meditation it's not
some like spaced
out old money payy home thing okay it's
not like that meditation is the struggle
to focus your mind on what you choose to
and the mind will fight you okay and the
more you fight with your mind you build
a muscle it's called a meditation muscle
and you get good on it okay you can
trick the mind too you know
like I don't know I I want to think
about tomorrow breakfast you know and
you're like oh good let's think about
tomorrow breakfast you don't fight this
is you can check the also what are you
going to have for breakfast uh I have
some pancakes and some eggs and aren't
you going to have coffee yeah must have
coffee too you know and then where where
do you get coffee coffee shops have you
been to a coffee shop
lately did you did you talk to anybody
there yeah yeah I did and then you
tricked the mind to come back
to the GU the kind thing that you did
okay so there's two ways to fight with a
m one is uh chicken to come back but
that's meditation that's real meditation
what happens is as you fall off to sleep
you fall off to sleep in a grateful mood
you're grateful for yourself you're
grateful for a new way of life you're
grateful and then all night long the
seed
multiplies in the subconscious
wildly okay I'm talking 250 million I
never intended to I never intended to
make a million I never thought it would
happen I didn't honestly think
about it but people ask me what's your
secret I say
[Music]
sleeping okay it's cool if you have the
right state of mind if you think about
the kindness you've done to others as
you fall asleep that cooks in your mind
all night okay it Cooks in your mind all
night then you can get other things I
mean money is one thing people want a
partner it's very very straightforward
there's no what do you call it
magic about it it's just a a plain old
thing you want a watermelon you take 12
watermelon seeds you punch your thumb in
the ground you dump the 12 in there you
cover it and you water it and that's the
end of it there's no fancy
thing and the same is true for a partner
you want a partner try this you will
always get a partner it cannot fail okay
uh find a lonely person step one I want
a partner step two find a lonely person
okay where do you find a lonely person
go to a nursing home okay any nursing
home I told thousands of people around
the world they all got boyfriends trust
me some of them got too many
boyfriends then they come back to me one
lady flew from a certain country in the
Middle East to Germany to complain to me
that she had too many
boyfriends uh after using this method
okay so be
careful uh find a a person like an
elderly person who's lonely and who has
no friends who has no family go to a Nur
nursing homes are hell Realms in this
world Sacramento has little hell Realms
they're called nursing homes we don't go
there nobody goes there they're very
very unpleasant they stink because
people can't hold their poo and pee and
people are desperate there they moan all
night and just go there pick one I have
one i' I've helped her for 20 years
she's still alive we're still
going uh pick one adopt them and help
them you don't have to go every week
even go every two weeks it doesn't
matter but but you know when you feed
birds or something what's the
trick you got to be regular you got to
be the same time they will start making
noise it's got to be 7: a.m. I don't
feed mine till 9:00 if I wake up at 7:00
I wait till 9:00 and they know it and
they don't get upset that they but by 9
they have at 9: they have it you know so
say I'll come every other
Friday and come every other Friday and
don't miss come at the same time and
just be with them just sit with them
that plants a seed that's like giving
money to
Bonnie you're aware of yourself going
plants a seed and then it grows and you
and a guy shows up in your life or a
girl or whatever okay it it's just the
uh the way it is you can't stop
it if you plant a seed if you water it
how do you water
it on your bed okay at night if you
plant it and if you water it you cannot
stop it there's no force in the world
that can stop it I quit my work uh I
don't know how many years
ago 15 years ago I stopped working 15
years ago the money is still coming the
money is still coming I was in a yoga
class dhamra in New York a guy gave me a
$100,000 check I never met him in my
life he handed me a $100,000 check I
like you I like your work I said I never
met you he said take it I said what's it
for he said anything you want you know
plant the seed and then go to
yoga no I'm not kidding you think I'm
kidding imagine if what I say is true
imagine how I feel to talk to you
imagine how it feels to me to see you
struggle for money you see imagine how
it feels if what I say is true imagine
how you laugh but I'm I'm like why are
they laughing of course you know just
plant the scene and you can't stop it it
will come it must come okay now last
question then we'll stop
okay and and maybe if you have some
questions I'll I'll take questions okay
about anything okay I don't care
here how does this relate to the six
problems we started with today I I'll go
there quickly let's go through them
quickly you cannot be sure about the
future from what I just said what
happens to number one go just plant what
you
want and it will come and you can't stop
it God cannot stop it okay if if you
plant a seed properly and you do your
work on your
hell no force in the universe can stop
that seat nobody nothing can stop it
okay you will get what
you good or bad by the way
sorry
uh dissatisfaction you know you struggle
to find a partner you find a partner and
then after 6 months you don't like them
anymore did it ever happen to
you that's because the seed wore out
okay the seed got old seeds wear out by
growing okay a tree kills a
s meeting your partner destroys the work
you did at the nursing
home got it every hour you spend with
them destroys more work from the nursing
home what's the solution more more keep
going okay it's dumb it's
obvious okay I I I had a woman uh this
worked for her she's a yoga teacher
she's an architect she's a famous you
know she got the boy I I went and did
the ceremony in New York and you know I
was it's very satisfying for me last
month I I married two people on the
stage in Singapore 1,200 people were
there they used this system and they met
each other they both used it and they
asked me if they could get married on
the stage and I was like that's kind of
weird but it was fun uh anyway I'm at
the wedding I'm sitting there on the
couch they're eating wedding cake I'm
like so how is Mrs
Smith at the nursing home and she's like
well you know
G getting married is not an easy thing
you know there's the wedding and
invitations there's the dress there's
the caterer you know I said like tell me
the truth how long's it been since
you've been in a nting home well I
didn't have time to go for 3 weeks you
know but unspoken was
what I got the boy who needs the old
lady you know I got the boy unspoken and
then I said you sit down and I got angry
I told the boy you come sit down next to
her you know and I said uh you got to go
together to the nursing home now now you
have to go together how long forever
forever how long you want to be then
you're going to use up the old lady get
another one
okay okay it won't end there's a
solution to number two okay things wear
out because the seeds
are wear out by producing their result
every hour you're with your men you have
used up more seeds it's a debit card and
you have to keep recharging that's
obvious that's easy that one's easy okay
number three you lose your jobs that's
the same principle okay if you keep
planting seeds a relation ship or an
occupation a career can go
indefinitely okay can the body go
indefinitely is the body like the pen or
not is the is the body coming from
you or it is it's like a pen it's the
same you perceive your body because of
seeds you have in your mind okay if you
could find the sage you could keep the
body going indefinitely
okay mortality is the you mortality is
the mortality is the running out of
seeds that you planted before and if you
want more life give
life give
life protect life there are many ways
right drive more carefully don't text
while you're driving don't use a cell
phone if that's conscious it will extend
your
life and and it can be indefinite okay
uh uh you have to start over again and
again not if you keep planning things
okay so you're the first four we took
care of right five minutes easy I should
have done it at the beginning
uh every job you get goes up and down
every day you have ups and downs in your
job every day you think things are going
well then suddenly the boss is unhappy
for no apparent reason right just when
you think you're doing well two things
happen to anybody in a big Corporation
what you get credit for stuff you never
did yeah then you're very quiet you're
[Laughter]
like and then you get blamed for stuff
you never do and then you're like very
noisy right it's everybody knows that uh
thingss don't have to go up and down
anymore if you use seeds okay you're
just experiencing old seeds popping up
and going away
okay get rid of
them collect new seeds powerful seeds
and then life will be consistent and
there won't be ups and downs okay very
beautiful very fun happy very happy okay
sometimes we're on the airplane flying
to China you know it's like I don't know
a flight 12-hour flight you know and
it's in the middle of the night and the
the stewardess comes by and says she sit
down on the arm rest and she say what do
you guys do you
know and and then sometimes I say can I
join your company CU we're like having a
really good time on the airplane and
they're like what do you do you know do
you need more people like that okay uh
number six in the end we are alone so I
put a nice quotation go to the last
page
so there's a there's an ancient uh
tradition in Tibet that Lord Buddha got
enlightened that Lord Buddha was very
close to getting enlightened and then he
had some subtle obstacle in his mind and
he couldn't make a breakthrough like
he's sitting under the bod tree right in
bodaya which at the time was called
vajas and uh he's sitting under the bodh
Bria and
uh he's meditating and he he can't do it
he can't break through the
final tiny thing he he can't do it so
there there's a tradition in Tibet that
says in India that says uh all the
Buddhists held a meeting the people who
already got enlightened which are
countless they had a meeting and they
said there's a guy on Earth he's trying
to get enlightened he's sitting under
some
tree what are we going to do he's got to
make a breakthrough and then they said
it's obvious he needs a partner you know
he needs a partner spiritual partner you
know and this is a the belief in our
tradition in the dam tradition this is
the belief that that the final
breakthrough has to be done with a
partner okay so so they like call this
lady her name was
til til UT and uh and they call on this
Angel and they said you okay there this
guy he's trying to get enlightened he
needs a breakthrough he need somebody to
help him meditate with him
and they sent her and she meditated with
him and there's this beautiful beautiful
story that uh when the sun came
up uh they got enlightened together you
know very beautiful story This is the
real story of how the Buddha got
enlightened okay it means that
uh it means that in our tradition at
least the partner is are very important
thing it's it's almost a path to
Enlightenment it's it's very good the
the reason everybody in the world wants
a partner is more deep than you suspect
it's not just a physical what do you
call it it's not procreation
alone it's there's a
deeper uh spiritual reason to have a
partner they complete
you uh chronically they they together
you complete each other okay and uh
spiritually you complete each other so
there's a
higher goals that's why people
crave partnership or crave companionship
it's not just physical or emotional it's
also very high spiritual thing they want
to be completed by another
person
uh so so then you just go to the nursing
home okay and you and you serve a lonely
person and and that will create a a
partner and that's beautiful she did did
she asked me I want to partner I I gave
her this talk she got married two months
ago it was very pleasant we all want I
helped to do the
ceremony it worked for her and it okay
she's a good
advertisement um last thing and then
I'll take questions if anybody wants to
stay you can stay and I'll take
questions if you want to go you can go
uh the most common question I get all
over the world in every every single
country and it's in the back of your
mind
now and I want to talk about it and in
today at lunch we talked about it uh it
seems I was in China in Guang Joo and a
lady raised her hand and she said okay I
understand your system you know I
understand I have to help someone make
money if I want money I have to help the
sick if I want to be healthy I
understand and I have to help the lonely
if I want to have a partner understand
your system it's logical it's comforting
to me that someone is is saying that
everything has a logic to it it's
Justice it feels very good that the
Universe should run by some kind of
cosmic Justice what you do to others
will be done to you it feels very
comfortable I like it this is a Chinese
person right and then they say
but our parents taught us something when
we were children in in China and I said
what and they said when you do a good
thing for someone don't ask for
something bad you know just do it
because it's kind and it's good and
don't don't like threaten people you
know I'll come to the nursing home if I
can get a boyfriend you know this is not
compassion this is business this is
boyfriend business you know I'll I'll
help you lonely old lady if I can get a
boyfriend out it if you help me get a
boyfriend I'll visit you but if not I'm
not interested you see then this is not
love this is some kind of selfishness
okay and I agree if you
use an older person to get a boyfriend
will you get a boyfriend or not
according to what I
said will there it comes up in the
scriptures okay if you give money to
someone only in order to get more money
will you get more money I'll give you
clue if you drop a pen with a noble
intention or if you drop a pen with a
selfish intention will it drop in both
cases it doesn't matter if you give
money you shall get money you can't stop
it okay if you help a lonely person or
boyfriend will come you can't stop it
but if you use her if you're
selfish what will the boyfriend be like
yeah okay he'll be a selfish son of a
gun okay you got to understand that
about this system you can't be selfish
and use this system will it work yes
will you be surrounded by creepy selfish
people as you have your Mercedes bz yes
and you've seen people they made money
and they're surrounded by creepy selfish
people so how do I get out of this
problem how do I make it
compassionate how do I make the process
of getting a boyfriend compassionate
okay and it's very
beautiful there's no
time
uh if you suddenly come up with a
boyfriend after what 5 years or
something of
losers you know you come up with a good
one then what are your friends going to
say they're going say what's the website
or you know
they're going to ask you what yoga
studio did you mean about you know what
I mean they're you're going to ask
you it's going to come up if suddenly
you have a lot of money they're going to
say what are you in the drugs or you
know what's happening with you know
where's all this coming from you know
they're going to ask you automatically
they're going to ask you your friends
are going to ask you and then they're
going to say what's the website or
where's the club and you're going to say
nursing home and then they're going to
say oh looks so
young and
uh if you are obviously
successful people will ask you what are
you doing how did you do that you know
you used to have a bad bag now you're
doing
yoga what happened what did you do and
then you're going to say oh I planted
some seeds and you're going to explain
to them this process if it works for you
okay give it a try I'm not going to you
know Force you give it a try life will
force
you okay you will lose things and you'll
you you'll get desperate and then you'll
try my system okay uh that's basically
how it works so um if it works for you
your friends will copy you and their
friends will copy them and then there
will be lines outside of nursing homes D
can I get an old lady today she's
they're all busy
next week what time 3:00 she's got a 15
minutes SL
open oh okay I'll be here next week I'll
be here early you know uh no there'll be
a big demand for lonely people I was in
Detroit I gave this dark this young man
came the second night he's like G I
found her what she's poor she's sick and
she's
lonely this old lady you know like good
job you know
and no you laugh because we avoid poor
people and we avoid the homeless or we
avoid people are really ill they you
take flowers a few times and then you
stop
going you know and older people are just
a drag you know so you don't go anymore
right uh in if if this became common
knowledge if people believed in this
system if it
works people will be struggling people
will be competing for poor
people people will be competing for old
people okay it's very sexy then what
will
happen po No More Lonely People no more
poor people God bless the last person to
understand the system because there
won't be anybody to help
left okay got it got it in Buddhism what
do they call that all you like Tibetan
Buddhists you struggle your whole life
with this thing what starts with the b o
d
body okay there's this Buddhist ideal
called bu love for the whole world it's
so hard to have it it's so what do you
call you can't get your mind around it
it's so hard to love the whole world I
can't even love my neighbor I can't even
love my dog you know how can I love the
whole world if you follow this system
the service of the whole world is an
automatic result you can't avoid
it got it it's so
cool you automatically are helping the
world if you follow this system because
people will copy you and then people
will copy them so if you keep your mind
on
that as you do it the first time you go
to the nursing home think I'm I'm
creating lines at nursing homes all over
the world right now I'm starting I'm
ground Z her of the boyfriend Revolution
you know I had a girl a lady in um
Eastern Europe she says oh this the reol
this will be boyfriend Revolution you
know and she was so happy and you got to
think like that think big okay by using
this system to get the things you want
in your life you are triggering a change
in in the global culture think like that
and it's
true and then no more selfish the
boyfriend will be
what deeply spiritual concerned about
the whole globe you know why cuz as you
helped the old lady you were thinking
about lines outside of nursing homes in
every country just put your mind there
it's the same action helping her is the
same action but the intention is
different I'm starting a virus I'm I'm
putting a virus out there think that way
okay and then the boyfriend will be
special the boyfriend will be
extraordinary got it then it then it's
not selfish it's the opposite of selfish
it's world love it's Global love it's
Global compassion it's
B okay it's very
cool the action is just visiting an old
lady and nursing home got it okay try
it don't be dumb I mean don't go home
and not try it that's really dumb you
wasted my time you wasted your time just
try it you know I'll marry you to the
guy next year okay all right any
questions like let's do 10 minutes of
questions and let's go home okay I got a
pack any questions no yes please can you
say it loud so people can hear what
happened with the go sitting on the gold
s laying on the gold sofa did you ever
get oh no he didn't hit me but he never
let me sit on it
again uh the sofa is still there he
passed away in 2004 but the the sofa is
still sitting there un nobody ever sat
on it since
then still there okay yeah please oh by
the way he has been
reborn as a child the child just entered
the monastery last
month uh he's a very precocious boy and
he loves
TV and uh his voice he's very very
naughty and so I'm like I'm like that's
him for sure the D Lama said it was him
uh you know so he has to approve all
these re in carnations
so it's cool he's a very naughty little
boy my
teacher yeah I I'm really learning a lot
about the process tonight and I'm
thinking about how cool it would be I
have two teenage kids and for teenagers
to understand this process there is
there some advice you can give me to
help them to learn this process yeah did
everybody hear that um
how do you teach this to teenagers or to
children or to anyone there's nothing
more powerful than J
Premier what is that J Premier living
example a living example we were in
Russia recently we were into that uh a
living example so you can talk to your
kids all you want you can lecture them
you can give them pamphlets from our
society and you can you know but in the
end they will copy what you do and and
nothing can change that you can say
anything you want they will ignore it
they will watch you and if you are
happy in a way the fact that the best
way to teach is by example is the
greatest pressure you can put on a
parent you see what I mean uh you not
only have to talk good you have to be
you have to be
successful so you know you're going to
get up and give this kind of talk you
better have made some money you better
have beautiful relationships and you
should be healthy even at an advanced
age except I didn't figure out the karma
for hair yet uh but uh but I mean
uh they'll watch you and they'll do what
you do so so the pressure is on you as a
parent as usual you know they you have
to if you are obviously
happy they will copy you and any
everybody will copy you and if you try
to teach and you're not
happy it'll there'll be a problem
there'll be a disconnect somewhere
people will say after a while they'll
get tired and they'll say it didn't work
for him it's not going to work for me I
have this joke about meditation to you I
will teach you meditation and everyone's
like I don't know what meditation you're
doing but I'll pass on that one
you know you have to be
uh so anyway that's I I heard the D Lama
tell tell somebody that you know as a
parent uh it's example and as any kind
of teacher you have to be good at what
you do and then people will imitate
you okay any other
question no okay let's go to bed I'd
like to thank uh Ami and Mark could you
stand up and yeah